Adrian Riches

5 Thomas Parkyn Close, Bunny, Nottinghamshire NG11 6QP Mobile: 07793 275099 / Email: mail@adyriches.co.uk

Profile

I am an IT support professional with over twenty years of technical support and customer service experience, a proven track record, considerable technical troubleshooting skills and a wide range of knowledge gained from providing IT and AV support to both higher education and the private sector.

I am a highly motivated, organised and resourceful individual with the ability to work under pressure and prioritise my workload, whether working alone or as part of a team. With a broad interest in IT and technology in general, I have demonstrated the ability to quickly grasp and adapt to new systems. The flexible approach to my duties I employ, along with the use of my initiative, makes me a valuable team member and the significant customer service skills I have gained, always ensure a positive customer experience. My excellent communication skills, both written and oral, enable me to effectively communicate with people at all levels.

I also have experience of providing IT support at multiple client sites and managing my own schedule to ensure that customer expectations are met or exceeded. The nature of the IT Support Technician role requires the ability to quickly grasp and adapt to new systems and services, and to be able to effectively support these systems within a minimum timescale. I would also be very keen to attend any training courses deemed necessary.

Knowledge/Experience/Skills

- Windows Server
- Exchange Server
- Active Directory Administration
- DNS, DHCP, TCP/IP
- Windows XP, 7, 8
- Mac OSX
- Linux
- HTML

MS Windows XP, 7, 8, Mac OSX, Windows Server, Linux (Ubuntu/CentOS) As part of my current and previous IT support roles, I have been responsible for installing, configuring and troubleshooting the above operating systems on PCs and servers in offices, computer rooms, test areas and laboratories, when attached to scientific equipment.

Installation training and support of standard and non-standard software packages I have provided IT support in both commercial and higher education environments. This has involved the installation, configuration, operation and troubleshooting of standard software such as MicroSoft Office, Windows and SPSS, and also non-standard software which, for instance, could control and collect the output from a microscope or monitor the temperature of frozen embryos.

Remote Access

A lot of the support I have provided has been delivered remotely. This has ensured efficient use of my time, and a swift positive solution for the client. I have also successfully configured PCs and related hardware for remote support, and rectified issues with connectivity to corporate networks, such as firewalls blocking specific ports etc

PC hardware

I have had a lot of exposure to PC hardware and have successfully diagnosed and repaired PCs by replacing physical components such as memory, hard disk drives, power supplies and motherboards, as well as by updating firmware to correct issues or to incorporate new features.

Web languages and databases

I have gained knowledge of web languages from training courses and personal study. I have created and administered websites for both my employer and clients, either by coding by hand or using applications such as Dreamweaver. I have also attended various database training courses, mainly on MicroSoft Access, and I am currently researching and self studying SQL.

Installation, interfacing and networking

During my time at Lindaven Services, I was responsible for specifying, installing and supporting PCs, servers and networks for both our clients and our own in-house systems. This involved installing routers, switches, patch panels and CAT5 cabling. I also installed and configured VPNs between remote locations and also remote backup solutions.

Work History

2019-Present

Installation & Support Specialist

Abbott Laboratories

- Responsible for the set up and the configuration of data management and E Learning systems in the point-of-care blood glucose hospital market.
- Responsible for the successful implementation of the ADC data management software on the accounts networks during installations and evaluation periods
- Troubleshooting system problems by remote access or on site
- Remote or on site diagnosis of complex problems

2013-2019

IT Research Support Manager

University of Nottingham - NIHR Nottingham Hearing Biomedical Research Unit

Acting as an IT advisor to NHBRU, supporting research activity and contributing to the design, setup and conduct of specific research projects through the provision of specialist IT advice. Managing NHBRU's local IT activities including responsibility for the Unit's internal inventory, website and research portal. I also provide local IT support to the centre which includes both standard and bespoke hardware, software and network support.

2008-2013

IT Support Assistant

University of Nottingham

Based at the Queens Medical Centre, Nottingham, I worked as part of a team responsible for providing an IT support and liaison service to the Medical School and other departments within the Faculty of Medicine and Health Science. This involved providing hardware and software support to end users and guests of the organisation both in person and remotely. During this period, I also completed a six month secondment to the IT Service Desk.

2006-2008

IT Support Technician Lindaven Services Ltd Lindaven Services provide contract IT support and related services to businesses across the East Midlands. My role involved providing an IT support and a technical sales service to our commercial customers. I provided onsite and remote hardware and software support to clients. I was also responsible for specifying and installing new IT systems including servers, networking and backup solutions.

1990-2005

Systems Manager & Sales Manager Nottingham Audio Visual Services Ltd

Nottingham Audio Visual Services Ltd provide audio visual presentation systems and professional video services to industry, healthcare and education. I gained a vast amount of customer service skills and technical experience during my time at Nottingham Audio Visual, where I spent a number of years as the Sales Manager heading up a small team. During this period I was responsible for specifying, quoting for and installing complex AV presentation and video systems. My latter years at Nottingham Audio Visual were spent as the Systems Manager, where I provided an IT support service to the company which included hardware and software support, website maintenance and on location IT support for large scale conference events as required by the Conference and Event Services Department.

Training

Institution: Robust IT / Details: MicroSoft SQL Server MCSA

Grade/Result: Attended / Date Awarded: May 2016

Institution: AXELOS/PEOPLECERT / Details: ITIL® Foundation in IT Service Management

Grade/Result: Pass / Date Awarded: May 2015

Institution: University of Nottingham / Details: CentOS Linux Systems Administration

Grade/Result: Completed / Date Awarded: Jan 2015

Institution: University of Nottingham / Details: ASPIRE Talent Management Programme

Grade/Result: Completed / Date Awarded: May 2014

Institution: University of Nottingham / Details: Advanced Queries using MicroSoft Access

Grade/Result: Completed / Date Awarded: Oct 2013

Institution: University of Nottingham / Details: Introduction to MicroSoft Access

Grade/Result: Completed / Date Awarded: Oct 2013

Institution: University of Nottingham / Details: Introduction to Database Design

Grade/Result: Completed / Date Awarded: Sept 2013

Institution: University of Nottingham / Details: Mac Support

Grade/Result: Completed / Date Awarded: July 2013

Institution: University of Nottingham / Details: SCCM 2012 Grade/Result: Pass / Date Awarded: Apr 2013

Institution: Institute of Leadership and Management / Details: Team Leading Award

Grade/Result: Pass / Date Awarded: Nov 2012

Institution: University of Nottingham / Details:

Agresso Grade/Result: Completed / Date Awarded:

Dec 2011

Institution: University of Nottingham / Details: Introduction to Programming

Grade/Result: Completed / Date Awarded: Mar 2011

Institution: University of Nottingham / Details: Mac Support

Grade/Result: Completed / Date Awarded: Oct 2009

Institution: University of Nottingham / Details: Project Management

Grade/Result: Completed / Date Awarded: Jun 2009

Institution: New Horizons / Details: HTML4
Grade/Result: Pass / Date Awarded: Nov

2001